Guide to the Christine Ricker Diaries
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Christine Ricker diaries
1941-1976
SC0422
Ricker, Christine.
1.5 Linear feet
Diaries with clippings, programs, notes, and letters concerning Stanford news and personalities, World War II and other political events, Ricker's activities in the Episcopal Church, and her circle of friends, most of whom were single working women like herself.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Rosamund Bacon, 1986.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Christine Ricker joined the Stanford staff in 1922; she served as director of the Student Union and the more than 40 campus dining halls from 1928 until her retirement in 1958. She also taught a course in "family living" through the School of Education. She graduated from Simmons College in 1917 with a degree in institutional administration; prior to coming to Stanford, she worked with the YWCA overseas. Ms. Ricker, who shared her campus home at 615 Mayfield Avenue with her lifelong companion Helen Vincent, died in 1986 at the age of 90.
Description of the Collection
The diaries of Christine Ricker date from December 1941 through April 1976; included within their pages were clippings, programs, notes, letters, and other items.
Some items are taped in; loose items have been removed and foldered.
The diary entries concern Stanford news and personalities, World War II and other political events, Ricker's activities in the Episcopal Church, and her circle of friends, many of whom were also single working women.
Access Terms
Ricker, Christine.; Diaries.; Single women.; Women--California.; Women--Social networks.
Collection Contents
- Diaries
  - Diary, December 7, 1941 - October 16, 1944, 1941-1944 (Box 1)
  - Diary, November 27, 1944 - June 5, 1950, 1944-1950 (Box 1)
  - Diary, August 11, 1950 - January 19, 1955, 1950-1955 (Box 1)
  - Diary, January 20, 1955 - December 31, 1957, 1955-1957 (Box 1)
  - Loose items from 12/41 - 10/44 diary, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Loose items from 11/44 - 6/50 diary, 1944-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Loose items from 8/50 - 1/55 diary, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Loose items from 1/55 - 12/57 diary, 195-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diary, January 1, 1958 - October 17, 1961, 1958-1961 (Box 2)
  - Diary, October 18, 1961 - November 29, 1964, 1961-1964 (Box 2)
  - Diary, December 2, 1964 - January 23, 1967, 1964-1967 (Box 2)
  - Diary, January 24, 1967 - September 30, 1968, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Loose items from 1/58 - 10/61 diary, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Loose items from 1/58 - 10/61 diary, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Loose items from 10/61 - 11/64 diary, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Loose items from 10/61 - 11/64 diary, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Loose items from 12/64 - 1/67 diary, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Loose items from 1/67 - 9/68 diary, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Diary, October 1, 1968 - March 14, 1970, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Diary, March 15, 1970 - December 31, 1971, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Diary, January 1, 1972 - March 20, 1974, 1972-1974 (Box 3)
  - Diary, March 21, 1974 - April 10, 1976, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Loose items from 10/68 - 3/70 diary, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Loose items from 3/70 - 12/71 diary, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Loose items from 3/70 - 12/71 diary, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Loose items from 1/72 - 3/74 diary, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Loose items from 1/72 - 3/74 diary, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Loose items from 3/74 - 4/76 diary, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)